Hello everyone and welcome to English Pod.
My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine and we're going
to have some fun today Marco, right?
That's right. Today we
are taking a small kid and
we're going to the park
and we're going to play.
Okay, so there are fun
things you can do at the park.
We're going to
learn all about them.
Let's take a listen to our dialogue.
Hey, honey, where were you?
I decided to take Kenny to
the park and get some fresh air.
How was it? Were there a lot of kids?
It wasn't too crowded, but we had a
great time. We got on the sea saw together,
then went on a couple of
different slides and then I
tried to go with him in the
jungle gym, but I didn't fit.
Sounds like fun. When we go, he
always just likes to play in the sandbox.
Yeah, but today he was really hyper.
He even got under the monkey bars.
And then he went on to go on the
swings for half an hour. I'm exhausted.
You should go to the park more often
since you don't go to the gym anymore.
Alright, we're back. So
now let's take a look at some
of this great playground
equipment on language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
So as you said, Marco,
today we're focusing in
language takeaway on some of
these things you can do at the park.
Now the first one is one of my personal
favorites from childhood called the sea saw.
The sea saw, that's
right. And so basically
it's that long piece
of, or sometimes metal,
or wood, and two people
sit at each opposite end.
Yes. And so when
one person goes down,
the other person goes up
and when that person goes
down, the other person
goes up. So it's a sea saw.
That's right. So yes, it's
actually a very common
toy that you can play
with at the playground,
but also another very common one. I'm sure
everyone knows and has been on is a slide.
A slide. Now this is a bit
hard to describe actually.
Slides are usually
quite colorful,
but they're like tubes that are
open and the child can go down.
So you're on top, maybe two meters high,
and then you go down the slide and you come
down to the ground.
That's right. And actually,
it's the noun a slide,
but what you do is the
verb is you actually
slide down the slide.
Yes. And sometimes you
go very fast and it's scary.
That's right. And well,
if you want to have
something a little bit less scary,
you can go into the jungle gym.
All right, jungle. Now the jungle is
actually a place. You know, in South America,
for example, you have
jungles with lots of trees
and monkeys and
things. But a jungle gym is
like many, many different
metal bars or wood
together to make
this open structure that
boys and girls can
climb on. So basically, you
start on the ground and
you climb all the way up
it. Okay. So I think this
is why it's called a kind
of like a jungle gym, right?
Because you can climb
up and down and
grab all these bars.
You can hang like a monkey
from the bars. Exactly. Yeah.
So basically, it's just a
cage that boys and girls
can climb on and
play with. Right.
And I guess you call it a jungle
gym because when you're doing
all this, you're doing
exercise. That's right.
All right. So now maybe
for the smaller kids,
we just want to play with
some toys. They can just
hang out at the
sandbox. All right.
This is one word, but
it's actually quite literal.
You'd have sand in a box.
That's right. And the sand box is
very safe and very fun
because boys and girls
can make castles or dig. But
there's nothing to it, really.
It's just a box. It's just a box
with sand literally. Yes, that's right.
So that's also fun for the
smaller kids to be at the sandbox.
Now going back to something very similar
to the jungle gym, we have the monkey bars.
Okay. Now monkey
bars are a very important
part of the park. These
are horizontal bars.
So they're across and you
hang on them with your arms.
So your body hangs
down. And when you hang,
your feet are off the
ground. It's very tall.
Right. And you have to
move. You have to change
from one bar to the
other. So it's like a ladder
that you're pulling
yourself across. Yes, exactly.
So you've probably
seen it exactly how you
describe it to ladder.
And you just got to hang
on to the different
bars with your arms.
It's actually quite difficult
to do. I always used to
get upset because I
couldn't go all the way across
because you know, you go
from one end to the other end.
But my arms will get so tired that I had
to drop down onto the ground. All right.
Well, something that's a
little bit less exhausting,
but also very fun when you go on
the swings. All right. Swings are great.
Now, swings are kind of like
chairs, but they don't have a back.
So you sit down on a
piece that's maybe plastic.
And I'm someone behind you will
push you because you're
on these these hanging chairs.
And they'll push you and
you go forward and backward.
And you can go very, very high.
And then you come
back down. Exactly.
So these are swings. All of
the, all of this equipment you've
most likely seen at
any of the, of the parks
that are nearby, but
we're going to post some
pictures as well. So
you can see more clearly
what they're all about.
Um, now let's go and
review the dialogue again
before we move on to
fluency builder. Hey,
honey, where were you?
I decided to take Kenny to
the park and get some fresh air.
How was it? Were
there a lot of kids?
It wasn't too crowded, but we had a
great time. We got on the sea saw together,
then went on a couple
of different slides.
And then I tried to go
with him in the jungle gym,
but I didn't fit.
Sounds like fun.
When we go, he always just
likes to play in the sandbox.
Yeah, but today
he was really hyper.
He even got under the monkey
bars. And then he went on
to go on the swings
for half an hour.
I'm exhausted. You should
go to the park more often
since you don't go
to the gym anymore.
All right, we're back. So
now let's take a look at three
phrases on fluency
builder. Fluency builder.
So our first phrase today
is actually something that
the, the parent
is talking about.
She wants to take Kenny to
the park and get some fresh air.
Now, what does it
mean to go get fresh air?
Well, basically you, it means
to go out and maybe walk
or just be outside and
get air from the outside.
Because sometimes you're
in your house all the time.
And that's not
fresh air. That's right.
So basically, this means
exactly what you're saying.
It means going outside.
So kids often need
to go get some fresh
air, but also adults do too.
Right. Sometimes I feel
like when I'm working in
the office for a long time, I
really need to get some fresh air.
So that means I go
outside for a walk.
Exactly. So you, and
you can tell your friends,
oh, excuse me for a minute, I'm
going to go get some fresh air.
Or you know what?
You're looking a
little bit pale. Maybe you
should go get some fresh air.
Exactly. And talking
about all this great
equipment and how much
fun you can have, the wife
said, wow, that
sounds like fun. Okay.
So sounds like fun.
It's not actually a sound.
It, this phrase is really
important because we say it a lot,
but it actually just
means that it sounds like it
will be a fun time. Right.
Or I think it will be fun.
Yeah. So from what you're
telling me, I think it's fun.
That's right. So we
can say this about
a lot of things. I could
say, hey, Marco, we're
going to go play some
football after work.
Do you want to come?
Sure. That sounds like fun.
All right. So he thinks it
sounds like a good idea.
You've probably come,
right? Exactly. So if something
sounds like fun. All
right. And moving on to
our last phrase that we
said that it was a great
idea that we're going to
the park and getting fresh
air because we don't go
to the gym anymore. Okay.
Now this is a really important
phrase to keep as a phrase.
First of all, we have a gym.
What do you do at a gym,
Marco? Well, you work out.
Yeah, you exercise. Maybe
you run on the treadmill
or you lift weights. But
it's important to remember
that the verb here
is to go to the gym.
So I could say, I go to the
gym three times a week. How
often do you go to the
gym? Okay. So that's the
phrase you go to the gym.
I stopped going to the gym
and I gained a
little weight. Okay.
So that's the way you use it.
You don't use any other verb,
but when you're talking
about the gym, you say
you go to the gym. I go to the
gym. He goes to the gym regularly.
All right. Very good. So that's all the
fluency builder for today. Let's review our
dialogue one last time.
Hey, honey, where were you?
I decided to take Kenny to
the park and get some fresh air.
How was it? Were
there a lot of kids?
It wasn't too crowded,
but we had a great time.
We got on the sea saw
together, then went on a
couple of different
slides, and then I tried to
go with him in the
jungle gym, but I didn't fit.
Sounds like fun. When we
go, he always just likes to
play in the sandbox. Yeah,
but today he was really hyper.
He even got under
the monkey bars,
and then he went on to go
on the swings for half an hour.
I'm exhausted. You
should go to the
park more often, since you
don't go to the gym anymore.
All right. So growing up, there are many,
many different games at parks that you can
probably find, especially
now you have such great
playground equipment,
but I think these are
the most basic ones that
everyone knows about.
That's right. These are pretty standard
things that you'll see at a playground.
I remember that a park doesn't
have to have these things.
Right. Parks are
just public places,
maybe with benches and
trees. But a playground is
the part of the park where you'll see these
kinds of things like a slide or swings.
And so it's important to
remember that they're not the same.
Right. Right. And now
did you ever have a bad
accident or did you fall
off the swing or the sea saw,
or maybe you fell off the
slide? Oh, I felt all the time.
It never is serious
accident, but swings,
I liked to swing. And
when I was forward, you
know, up in the air, I
used to let go and jump.
You would jump off the swing.
I would jump off the swing.
So when you're very high in the air,
it feels like you're flying for a minute.
My mother hated it because she thought I
was going to break my arms, but I loved it.
It's great fun. And actually,
we would really like to know,
maybe you have some
pictures that you can share
with us of some specific
playground equipment that
we may have missed.
There are a lot of things
out there, and maybe
locally, there are even some
more fun things that we
don't have. So let us know
what do playgrounds
look like in your country.
We hope to see you at EnglishPod.com.
All right. We'll see you guys there. Bye.